Gibson Berglund

4804 16th Ave S
Minneapolis, MN
(612) 695-1919
berglundgibson@gmail.com
www.linkedin.com/in/gibson-berglund/

Full stack web developer with a background in teaching language, as well as an education in psychology. Earned a certificate in Full Stack Web Development from the University of Minnesota. Highly proficient communicator and creative problem-solver, natural team player, a lot of experience in working with people from different backgrounds and perspectives.

Skills

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript ES6+, SQL, MySQL, NoSQL, MongoDB, Express, Node, Handlebars, React, Github

Experience

October 2019 - March 2022

Smooth Talkers, English as a Second Language Teacher - Santiago, Chile

- Individual and group lessons for adults and children of varying proficiency levels
- Prepared lessons tailored to student's specific needs
- Monitored progress and wrote student reports with suggestions for continued learning

March 2018 - December 2018

Freelance, English as a Second Language Teacher - Santiago, Chile

- Individual lessons for adults of varying proficiency levels
- Prepared lessons tailored to student's specific needs

November 2016 - June 2019

Esker Grove Restaurant, Food Expeditor - Minneapolis, MN

- Ensured timely and professional presentation of food to the customer according to fine-dining standards
- Facilitated communication between servers, chefs, support staff, and management

January 2016 - September 2016

Ecopolitan Restaurant, Server and Chef - *Minneapolis, MN*

- Prepared raw vegan meals from scratch using Earth-friendly methods
- Hosted, seated, and served customers

Education

University of Minnesota, Certificate in Full Stack Web Development - Minneapolis, MN

- Thorough training and hands-on application of many essential web development tools, including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL, MongoDB, Handlebars, React
- Extensive drilling in industry standards and best practices, such as group collaboration through Github
- Overview of computer science principles related to web engineering and best practices in coding

University of Cambridge, Certificate in Teaching English as a Second Language – Taken in Minneapolis, MN, through The Teaching House

- Intensive training in student-centered learning
- 120 hour course including teaching practice to intermediate level students, lesson planning, observation of experienced teachers, peer observation and feedback

University of Iowa, Bachelor of Arts in Anthropology and Psychology - Iowa City, IA